Guide to the South Africa Now Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Miscellaneous PAL Tapes, 1988-1990, undated; Series XII
  - Tape M369: Winne Mandela and other interview, 1989 December; 1 (Box 2223)
    Title on case, "Shoka Taal monument to Afrikaans language," is incorrect.
  - Tape M370: Pik Botha, 1989 December; 1 (Box 2224)
  - Tape M373: Winne Mandela press conference; Sisulu Interview; Wolpe press conference, Undated; 1 (Box 2225)
  - Tape M373: Helen Joseph visits Nelson Mandela, interview outside the prison, 1989 December 21; 1 (Box 2226)
  - Tape M374: Education crisis meeting; interview with Peter Magubane, 1990 July 1; 1 (Box 2227)
  - Tape M374: Journalists under apartheid, Undated; 1 (Box 2228)
  - Tapes M375-M376: King Leka, Undated; 2 (Box 2229–2230)
  - Tape M377: Angola, Undated; 1 (Box 2231)
  - Tape M378: Sisulu, Lusaka, Undated; 1 (Box 2232)
  - Tape M381: Joe Slovo, Undated; 1 (Box 2233)
  - Tape M382: Jesse Jackson, 1990 February 10; 1 (Box 2234)
  - Tape M385: Peter and Stewart interview, 1990 February 10 or October 2; 1 (Box 2235)
  - Tapes M386-M387: Gabu Tagwana, 1990 February 10; 2 (Box 2236–2237)
  - Tape M388: Anton Harber, editor of Weekly Mail, 1990; 1 (Box 2238)
  - Tape M389: Zwelakhe Sisulu, Undated; 1 (Box 2239)
  - Tapes M391-M392: Mandela rally; release; rally in Soweto, 1990 February 13; 2 (Box 2240–2241)
  - Tape M393: Mandela interview, 1990 February 15; 1 (Box 2242)
  - Tape M395: Globalvision dubs, Undated; 1 (Box 2243)
  - Tape M396: Mandela release, Soweto, 1990 February 16; 1 (Box 2244)
  - Tapes M397-M403: Allister Sparks interview with Nelson Mandela, 1990 February 23; 7 (Box 2245–2251)
  - Tape M404: Back to the Motherland -- documentary, 1990 March 30; 1 (Box 2252)
  - Tape M405: Wind of Hope -- documentary, 1990 March 30; 1 (Box 2253)
  - Tapes M406-411: TransAfrica dinner in Los Angeles, 1990 April 4; 6 (Box 2254–2259)
  - Tape M412: South African Broadcasting Corporation (SABC) stories, Undated; 1 (Box 2260)
  - Tape M413: Domestic workers (from VNS), 1990 May 31; 1 (Box 2261)
  - Tape M415: Chicco; Bright Blue; Mango Groove; "The People Want Mandela," "Our World" (Lizard Post Production), 1990 June 12 or December 6; 1 (Box 2262)
    The audio on the last ten minutes of the tape is defective.
  - Tape M416: Mandela visits Khayelitsha, 1990 November 30; 1 (Box 2263)
- Mandela in America, 1990; Series XIII
  The series consists of footage taken for the documentary Mandela in America, a film that documents Nelson Mandela's visit to the United States in 1990, after his release from prison. The footage includes both public and private moments from Mandela's speaking tour. It is arranged sequentially by a tape numbering system used by Globalvision and tape titles used by Globalvision have been preserved.
  - Tape MA3: Mandela at John F. Kennedy (JFK) airport, 1990 June 20; 1 (Box 2264)
  - Tape MA7: Airport pool footage, 1990 June 20; 1 (Box 2265)
  - Tape MA10: Boys and Girls High School, 1990 August 9; 1; videotape (v-30h) (Box 2266)
  - Tapes MA10-M11: Brooklyn motorcade, 1990 June 20; 2 (Box 2267–2268)
    The same tape number was assigned to two different recordings (MA10).
  - Tapes MA14-MA15, MA16a, MA17: Ticker tape parade, 1990 June 20; 4 (Box 2269–2272)
    Title on case and tape cartridge for Tape MA 16a (box 2271): "City Hall reception for Mandela."
    Tape MA17 (box 2272) contains no audio.
  - Tape MA19: Harlem rally, [1990]; 1 (Box 2273)
  - Tapes MA19-MA20, MA22: City Hall, 1990 June 20; 3 (Box 2274–2276)
    The same tape number was assigned to two different recordings (MA19).
  - Tape MA28: Mandela in Harlem, 1990 June 21; 1 (Box 2277)
  - Tape MA28: Harlem -- speech, drums; 28 children in auditorium, [1990]; 1 (Box 2278)
  - Tapes MA31, MA34-MA35, MA37-MA39: Mandela at Yankee Stadium, 1990 June 21; 6 (Box 2279–2284)
  - Tapes MA41-MA42: Mandela at Interfaith Church, 1990 June 22; 2 (Box 2285–2286)
  - Tapes MA50-MA51: Mandela at Riverside Church, 1990 June 21; 2 (Box 2287–2288)
  - Tapes MA56-MA63: Mandela at United Nations (UN), 1990 June 22; 8 (Box 2289–2296)
  - Tapes MA67-MA68: Winnie Mandela at Brooklyn Academy of Music, 1990 June 22; 2 (Box 2297–2298)
  - Tape MA71: Interviews with Salt (of Salt-n-Pepa), Vernon Reed, Harry Allen, Hudlin Brothers, and Nelson George about Mandela in United States, 1990; 1 (Box 2299)
  - Tape MA75: Mandela in New York -- anti-apartheid meeting, Council on Foreign Relations, other CNN news reports from various countries, 1990; 1 (Box 2300)
  - Tapes MA78-MA80: Mandela in Boston at Madison Park High School; Paul Simon interview, 1990 June 23; 3 (Box 2301–2303)
  - Tapes MA84-MA85: Mandela in Boston and concert with Michelle Shocked, Ted Kennedy, and Ray Flynn, 1990 June 23; 2 (Box 2304–2305)
  - Tapes MA86-MA88: Mandela in Los Angeles, 1990 June 29; 3 (Box 2306–2308)
    The same tape numbers were assigned to two different recordings (MA87-MA88).
  - Tapes MA87-MA90: Mandela in Boston with Mandela speech, dance, and Michelle Shocked, 1990 June 23; 4 (Box 2309–2312)
  - Tapes MA92-MA96: Mandela in Boston -- Greatest Hits; Winnie Mandela interview, 1990 June 23; 5 (Box 2313–2317)
  - Tapes MA101-MA103: Mandela in Washington and with the AFL-CIO; Mandela at United States Congress, 1990 June 25; 3 (Box 2318–2320)
  - Tape MA108: Mandela in Miami, 1990 June 28; 1 (Box 2321)
  - Tapes MA111-MA113: Mandela in Detroit, including with United Auto Workers (MA111), 1990 June 28; 3 (Box 2322–2324)
  - Tape MA126: Jeff Cohen interview on Mandela and the CIA, 1990; 1 (Box 2325)
  - Tape MA127: Mandela release, 1990; 1 (Box 2326)
  - Tape MA128: Mandela in Sweden, 1990 June; 1 (Box 2327)
  - Tape MA130: Interview with Charlene Hunter Gault, 1990 July 25; 1 (Box 2328)
  - Tapes MA131-MA132: Mandela in the Netherlands, 1990 June 25; 2 (Box 2329–2330)
    Tape MA132 (box 2330) contains left channel audio noise throughout; right channel is unaffected.
- South African Tourism Board, 1983-1988, undated; Series XIV
  The series consists of videotapes created by the South African Tourism Board and used in the production of various episodes of South Africa Now. It is arranged sequentially by a tape numbering system used by Globalvision and tape titles used by Globalvision have been preserved.
  - Tape Q1: More Than An Investment, source: Audience Planners, 1984; 1 (Box 2331)
  - Tape Q2: History of South Africa, 1983; 1 (Box 2332)
  - Tape Q3: South Africa: The Mainstay of the Southern African Region, 1986; 1 (Box 2333)
  - Tape Q4: "The Best Kept Secret", Undated; 1 (Box 2334)
  - Tape Q5: The World and South Africa in the 1990s, 1987; 1 (Box 2335)
  - Tape Q6: South Africa Today: A Question of Power, 1986; 1 (Box 2336)
  - Tape Q7: South Africa: The Solution, 1986; 1 (Box 2337)
  - Tape Q8: Love Changes People and People Change Things, Undated; 1 (Box 2338)
  - Tape Q9: South African Rebuttal to "Suffer the Children", Undated; 1 (Box 2339)
  - Tape Q10: South African Broadcasting Corporation (SABC): Story on AIDS, 1988 December 7; 1 (Box 2340)
  - Tape Q11: Lake Wilderness - South African Tourist Board, Undated; 1 (Box 2341)
  - Tape Q12: The Peace Game - South African Tourist Board, Undated; 1 (Box 2342)
  - Tape Q13: On the Third Day - South African Tourist Corporation, Undated; 1 (Box 2343)
  - Tape Q14: South Africa for the Visitor, Undated; 1 (Box 2344)
- Footage from Independent Producers from South Africa, Produced by Afravision, 1984-1989, undated; Series XV
  The series consists of videotapes created by independent South African producers, which was used during the production of South Africa Now. It is arranged sequentially by a tape numbering system used by Globalvision and tape titles used by Globalvision have been preserved.
  - Tape R3: Challenge to the Churches; Mayday; The Report Is Censored; Women Awake, Undated; 1 (Box 2345)
  - Tape R4: Stayaway, 1988 June 21; 1 (Box 2346)
  - Tape R5: Zwelakhe Sisulu; Govan Mbeki, 1988 June 22; 1 (Box 2347)
    The audio on the tape weakens after 20 minutes of content.
  - Tape R6: Before Dawn -- Amsterdam Conference, International Defence and Aid Fund (IDAF), 1988 June 21; 1 (Box 2348)
  - Tape R7: Zilivia Ziya Etsheni -- Compelling Freedom, Worker Culture, tape number 90, [No year] July 11; 1 (Box 2349)
  - Tape R8: Poet, tape #63, [No year] July 11; 1 (Box 2350)
  - Tape R10: South Africa Workers/Unions/Health; May Day Strike; Women Awake; Alexandra Township report, Undated; 1 (Box 2351)
  - Tape R11: September compilation (Khotso House, consulate story); Metal Workers Strike, 1988 September 30; 1 (Box 2352)
  - Rape R12: Rushes for municipal elections (tapes 136a and b), 1988 October 19; 1 (Box 2353)
  - Tape R14: Footage shots of Capetown; street scenes in Athlone/Mowbray; Capetown commuters; Boesak and Tutu preaching; Janet Cherry with consumer boycott campaigner; MKuzeli Cherry at Port Elizabeth funeral, 1988 December 6; 1 (Box 2354)
  - Tape R15: Interview with Harry Gwala, 1988 December 2; 1 (Box 2355)
  - Tapes R16-R17: Winnie Mandela press conference, [re: birthday; banning], 1988; 2 (Box 2356–2357)
  - Tape R18: David Bruce, conscientious objector, 1988; 1 (Box 2358)
  - Tape R19: Certain Unknown Persons, 1988 December 16; 1 (Box 2359)
  - Tape R20: Zwelakhe Sisulu interview, 1984 November; 1 (Box 2360)
  - Tape R21: Soweto Education Crisis, 1989 April 28; 1 (Box 2361)
  - Tape R22: Namibian Exiles Return Home, 1989 July; 1 (Box 2362)
- South African Footage, 1989-1990; Series XVI
  The series includes a small number of miscellaneous tapes. It is arranged sequentially by a tape numbering system used by Globalvision and tape titles used by Globalvision have been preserved.
  - Tape S12: Soweto Education Crisis, Afravision, 1989; 1 (Box 2363)
  - Tape S13: National Union of Mineworkers (NUM) Congress, parts 1 and 2, 1989 April; 2 (Box 2364–2365)
  - Tape S14: Farewell concert -- Ladysmith Black Mambazo, Ray Phiri and Stimela, Chicco, 1989 April 30; 1 (Box 2366)
  - Tape S15: National Protest Day -- May Day rally, 1989 April 30; 1 (Box 2367)
  - Tapes S224-S225: Mandela rally (Soweto), 1990 February 16; 2 (Box 2368–2369)
- Reports about South Africa Now, 1980s-1990s; Series XVII
  The series includes a small number of videotapes from other television news sources about the program South Africa Now. It is arranged sequentially by a tape numbering system used by Globalvision and tape titles used by Globalvision have been preserved.
  - Tape T2: WVCB report on South Africa Now: "Inside South Africa Now ", [Circa 1988-1991] June 20; 1 (Box 2371)
  - Tape T4: MTV news report on South Africa Now, Circa 1988-1991; 1 (Box 2372)
  - Tape T5: Today Show interview with Carolyn Craven, 1989 February 14; 1 (Box 2373)
  - Tape T6: Eleventh Hour on South Africa Now, 1989 February 22; 1 (Box 2374)
  - Tapes T8-T9: Evening Magazine with South Africa Now segment, 1989 April; 2 (Box 2375–2376)
  - Tape T10: CNBC Media Beat, Circa 1988-1991; 1 (Box 2377)
  - Tape T11: All About TV with Carolyn Craven and Mweli Mzizi, Circa 1988-1991; 1 (Box 2378)
  - Tape T12: George Polk Awards, 1991 April 17; 1 (Box 2379)
- Miscellaneous Unnumbered Tapes, 1987-circa 1990; Series XVIII
  - Bush and Mandela in Washington; CIA, 1990 June 14; 1 (Box 2380)
    The audio on the tapes drops for approximately one minute at 9:50 minutes.
  - South African music video (English/Afrikaans), Undated; 1 (Box 2381)
    The tape contains no audio after first 4 minutes of content.
  - Stevie (Wonder?) performs, Detroit, 1990 July 13; 1 (Box 2382)
  - Jesse Jackson and Oliver Tambo at People United to Serve Humanity (PUSH) headquarters, Chicago, 1987 January; 1 (Box 2383)
- Paper Logs and Publicity Files, Circa 1988-1994; Series XIX
  The series includes paper logs of programs and videotapes, and publicity files compiled by Globalvision staff. The series also includes an index of program highlights.
  - Paper logs
    - Inventories (Box 2384, Folder 1-2)
    - Short Reports (C series), Circa 1988-1994 (Box 2384, Folder 3-4)
    - Documentaries (D series) (Box 2384, Folder 5-6)
    - Stock Footage (E series), Circa 1988-1994 (Box 2385, Folder 1-2)
    - Interviews (F series)
      - F1-F90 (Box 2385, Folder 3-7)
      - F91-F317, Circa 1988-1994 (Box 2386, Folder 1-7)
      - F319-F457, Circa 1988-1994 (Box 2387, Folder 1-6)
      - F458-F860, Circa 1988-1994 (Box 2388, Folder 1-7)
      - F861-F1068, Circa 1988-1994 (Box 2389, Folder 1-3)
    - Culture (G series) (Box 2389, Folder 4)
    - American Protest (H series) (Box 2389, Folder 5)
    - United Nations TV (K series) (Box 2389, Folder 6)
    - Stills and Footage (L series), Circa 1988-1994 (Box 2390, Folder 1)
    - Mandela in America (MA series) (Box 2390, Folder 2)
    - Duke conference (P series) (Box 2390, Folder 3)
    - South African Tourism Board (Q series) (Box 2390, Folder 4)
    - Afravision (R series) (Box 2390, Folder 5)
    - South African Footage (S series) (Box 2390, Folder 6-9)
    - Reports about South Africa Now (T series) (Box 2390, Folder 10)
    - Unnumbered logs (Box 2390, Folder 11-13)
  - Miscellaneous notes (not inclusive), Circa 1988-1991
    Consists of notes on individual tapes.
    - C-Duke (Box 2390, Folder 14)
    - F20-F1061 (Box 2390, Folder 15-18)
    - G-P (Box 2390, Folder 19)
    - Unidentified (Box 2390, Folder 20)
  - "Highlights of Weekly Shows" [index to episodes], 1991 (Box 2391, Folder 1)
  - Publicity files and clippings related to South Africa Now, Circa 1988-1994 (Box 2391, Folder 2-136)
  - Articles by Danny Schechter, Circa 1988-1994 (Box 2391, Folder 137-140)
  - Miscellaneous, Circa 1988-1994 (Box 2391, Folder 141-142)